Hayden Cai

Full Stack Developer

Address Melbourne, VIC 3000

Phone 041-078-0822

E-mail ianyaheng822@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/hengcai/

I am a self-driven front-end developer and have been in the industry for 3.5 years. have a keen eye for detail and most of my working life has been dedicated to creating stunning websites for clients. Equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, Restful API etc. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

Profile

https://haydencai.netlify.app/

Work History

2022-04 - Current

Software Developer

Exco Parters, Melbourne, VIC

Working with Bendigo and Adelaide Bank

- Stack used includes styled-components, Typescript, Next.js,
 React(hooks,reducer), GraphQL, Apollo Client, BFF(Backends For Frontend Pattern), TypeGraphQL, Material-UI, Formik,API Gateway
- Designed and implemented a GraphQL API experience layer that integrates Node.js RESTful API microservices.
- Implemented the front end in React.js, TypeScript, and Apollo GraphQL, configured with Webpack, Babel, and Eslint.
- Wrote unit testing for React component by using Jest

2020-08 - Current

Front End Developer

Arkade, Melbourne, VIC

- Stack used includes HTMLS, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Sass, Less, Typescript, Next.js, React(hooks,reducer), GraphQL, Shopify Plus, Prismic (Content Management System), Algolia, Vercel built for Next.js, Zendesk
- Assisted in building reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Collaborated with designer, product, and back-end teams to make sure the code implementation meet design requirements, business specifications.
- Worked as client support to provide effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.

Full Stack Developer(intern) 2020-06 - 2020-08

SettleEasy, Melbourne, VIC

- Stack used includes HTMLS, CSS3, React, StoryBook, MySQL, Nodejs
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.

Front End Developer(Intern) 2019-04 - 2019-05

JR Academy, Melbourne, VIC

- Implemented web application with reactJS, JavaScript(ES6), jQuery,HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap 4, and responsive design.
- Utilized Postman, Trello, InVision and interactive mockup to aid development, testing and documentation generation for project

Education

Diploma of Information Technology: Web Development Coding 2019-08 - 2020-01 Bootcamp(full-time)

Coder Academy - Melbourne

Recipient of Women Technology Scholarship

• Coursework in JavaScript, React, Node.is, Ruby on Rails

2019-01 - 2019-03 Front End Development

JR Academy - Melbourne

Coursework in JavaScript, React, Node.js, C#

Bachelor of Design 2009-08 - 2013-08

Southwest Forestry University - China

Skills

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript(ES6), GraphQL, Apollo Client, BFF(Backends For Frontend Pattern), TypeGraphQL, Material-UI, TypeScript, iQuery, Next.is, ReactJS (hooks, reducer), Typegraphal,

Back End: node is

Database: mySQL, MongoDB

Develops Tools & Platforms: Jira, Github, Gitlab, Postman, Jira Methodologies: Agile, Figma, Prismic, Shopify Partner, in Vision

Other: Restful API, GraphQL, Shopify API